海莉 快点儿 你要迟到了
Haley,hurry up! You are gonna be late.
艾丽克斯 你在干嘛
Alex, what are you doing?
我要记录下海莉的第一次"铁链劳役"行为
I need to document Haley's first standard chain gang.
那不是铁链劳役
It's not a chain gang.
那是社区服务 别烦她了
It's community service. And leave her a lone.
她心情已经够糟糕的了
She feels bad enough as it is.
我快精神分裂了 一方面 我一想到
Okay, I'm torn. On one hand, I'm like,
我得捡一整天垃圾 好烦
"Ugh, I have to pick up garbage all day."
但是另一方面 我又想着
And on the other hand, I'm like,
我穿这身橘红色真好看
"Look at me in orange."
真漂亮 发给我
Aw, that's cute. Send that to me.
海莉在学校里犯了点法
Haley had a little run-in with the law in college.
她因袭警被捕
She was arrested for assaulting a police officer.
纯属意外 我摔在他身上
Accidentally. I fell on him.
当时正因为低龄饮酒而逃避逮捕
While evading arrest for underage drinking.
那个是故意的
That was on purpose.
他们对她宽大处理
They were very lenient with her.
现在她只需做一些社区服务
She only has to do community service.
因为本小姐没有前科哦
Because I do not have any priors.
你对此有点太得瑟了 宝贝女儿
Taking a little too much pride in that, sweetheart.
外面的世界非常危险
Things can get pretty rough out there.
我实在弄不到香烟
I couldn't get my hands on any cigarettes.
但我用一把旧小刀做成了一把尖刀
But I did make you a shiv out of an old knife.
你不可能用一把小刀做成一把尖刀
You don't make a shiv out of a knife.
是啊 你可以用锈汤匙或者玻璃碎片做成尖刀
Yeah, you make a shiv out of a rusty spoon or a shard of glass.
或者是人的股骨
Or a human femur.
没错 时刻保持创意
Exactly. Be creative.
你真贴心 卢克
It's really sweet of you, Luke,
不过那里都是些酒驾司机和
But there's just gonna be a bunch of drunk drivers
蠢到会被抓现行的"破坏者"而已
and vandalizers who were stupid enough to get caught.
或者蠢到说"破坏者"的人
Or stupid enough to use the word "Vandalizers."
应该说"破坏分子"
It's vandals.
众人皆蠢我独聪
I'm so alone.
他们会生吃了你 乡巴佬们
They're gonna eat you alive, suburbia.
米奇尔 我们回来了
Mitchell, we're back.
你肯定会觉得难以置信
You are not going to believe this.
小卡 还记得我为什么不让你
Cam, do you remember why I didn't want you
把莉莉衣柜的把手拆掉吗
to swap out the handles on Lily's dresser?
因为你缺乏设计者的眼光 而且害怕改变
Because you lack a designer's eye and fear change?
不 是因为我担心两星期之后
No. Because I was afraid two weeks would go by,
我们还在用小铲子
and we'd still be using a spatula
来拿莉莉的衣服
to get at Lily's clothes.
好吧 现在有个更严重的问题
Okay, well, we have bigger issues.
猜猜他们今天在公园里砍掉了什么
Guess what they are cutting down at the park today?
-树吗 -对 你怎么知道
- A tree? - Yes. How did you know that?
我"预感"超准
I played a hunch.
不是普通的树 而是那棵"欧娜树"
Not just any tree, Tree-ona elmsly.
不是吧 太糟了 那可是我们野餐专用树啊
Oh, no. That's terrible. That's our picnic tree.
简直是噩梦
It's a nightmare.
小姑娘遗传了她老爸爱夸张的毛病哦
Well, someone's picked up her daddy's gift for hyperbole.
他们要锯掉一片天堂
They are literally chainsawing paradise
-来建一座停车场 -太糟糕了
- to put up a parking lot. - Oh, it's too bad.
我们得采取点措施
We have to do something.
如果我们早点知道 是可以
Well, if we knew earlier, we could.
我很自责 我揽了太多事
I blame myself. I've taken on too much.
你揽了哪些事来着
What exactly have you taken on?
你开什么玩笑 上音乐课
Are you kidding me? Teaching music?
拆掉这个把手 出演音乐剧
This dresser handle project? My role in the musical?
哎呀那个噢
Oh, that.
知道吗 我不喜欢你的语气
You know what? I don't like your tone.
替角儿在任何演出中都最具挑战性
The understudy's the most challenging role in any production.
你必须时刻准备上场
You have to be ready at a moment's notice
去面对一群失望的观众
to go on and face a disappointed audience
他们本来是想看肯尼·范·海辛顿的
who was there to see Kenny Van Heffington.
那个卖保险的吗
Our insurance guy?
他的表演激动人心
He's breathtaking.
-是吗 -好吧 我恨他
- Really? - Yeah, I hate him.
无所谓了 我刚刚在说什么
Anyway, what was I talking about?
给衣柜装上新把手
Putting new handles on the dresser.
对了 树的问题 我得采取点措施
Right. The tree. I have to do something.
这样的日子我过不下去了
I can't live like this.
曼尼 你再磨蹭我们就老了
Manny, while we're young!
他不想去
He doesn't want to go.
所以他才精心打扮了这么长时间
That's why he's taking so long with the primping.
像他这么大的男孩子根本不该打扮
A boy his age should do exactly zero primping.
你准备好了吗
You ready?
完全没有
Not in the least.
就该这样
That's the spirit.
我班上有个同学 道格·布鲁克斯
This kid in my class, Doug Brooks,
每年都要举办运动主题的生日派对
has a sports-themed birthday party every year.
全是男生 全是运动 全天不停
All boys. All sports. All day.
他称之为"道林匹克"
He calls it the Doug-lympics,
可那也得他每4年举办一次
which might make sense if he did it every four years,
或者他名叫"奥"才说得通啊
or if his name was Al.
我只能说 一切都是狗屁不通
Let's just say nothing about it works.
曼尼 今天天气很好
Manny, it's a beautiful day outside.
去吧 享受你的道林匹克
Go on. Enjoy your Dougy-lympics.
你不用非得赢奖牌 找点儿乐子就行
You don't have to win a medal. Just have fun.
无论如何道格总会赢得最多的奖牌
Doug finishes with the most medals no matter what.
而且我觉得他邀请我
Plus I think he only invites me
只是因为他喜欢将肤色与国家联系起来
because he likes to match skin color to nation.
艾伦·严就是因此才会被邀请的
I know that's why Alan Yan gets invited.
我们明白的 运动不是你的强项
Okay, we get it. Sports isn't your thing.
但你有时候得走出自己的"舒适小世界"
But you gotta step out of your comfort zone sometime.
看在老天爷的份上
And for god sake,
把这双尖头鞋换了吧
change out of those wingtips.
你还是个小孩子 不是沙滩上的尼克松
You're a kid. You're not Nixon on the beach.
好吧 我去换"运动专用鞋"
Fine. I'll put on my sporty shoes.
在哪儿来着
Where are they?
在鞋盒里尚未拆封
They're still in the box.
别忘了在你穿鞋子之前
And don't forget to take out the paper
把塞在里头的纸拿出来 好吗
before you put them on, okay?
而且那就叫运动鞋
And they're called sneakers.
大家好啊
Hello, hello!
歌洛莉亚 准备好出发了吗
Hey, Gloria. So, ready to go?
-去哪儿 -不是说好了去逛好市多吗
- Where? - Thought we were doing a Costco run.
我明白了
Oh, I see what this is.
你打电话叫克莱尔来照顾我这个傻瓜孕妇
You called Claire to babysit the stupid pregnant lady!
是你打电话给她的
You're the one who called her.
我有吗
I did?
我打给克莱尔的
I called Claire.
得有人看着歌洛莉亚
Gloria needs watching.
她的孕期健忘症很严重
She's got a serious case of pregnancy brain.
上周我在冰箱里找到一块肥皂
Last week, I found a bar of soap in the fridge
在浴室看到一块黄油
and a stick of butter in the shower.
我洗完一整天浑身都是爆米花般的黄油味
I walked around all day smelling like a bucket of popcorn.
总比我吃的"肥皂吐司"强
Better than the toast I ate.
那你还吃了两块
Yet you ate the second piece.
杰 拜拜了 我们走了
Jay! Bye-bye! We're leaving!
不是吧你 我就站在这呢
Seriously? I'm right here.
下蹲 下蹲 揍他 你个小怪胎
Duck! Duck! Come on and hit him, you little freak!
那也敢号称是左勾拳
Talk about a big left hook.
天呐 我爱你
God, I love you.
菲尔填空
Phil in the blank!
比尔法案
Bill of rights!
老杰瑞
Jerry-atric!
艾伦他爹
Alan's dad!
伙计们 卢克 你准备好了吗
Hey, guys. Luke, you getting in there?
当然
Of course.
看呐 又让我代表墨西哥队
Look, I'm Mexico. Again.
到底有没有人在乎 我不是墨西哥来的
Does anybody care that I'm not from mexico?
你总那么说
You keep saying that,
不过我们谁也没看过你的出生证明
but we've never seen a birth certificate.
好了 我5点钟会过来接你
All right, look, I'll pick you up at 5:00.
玩得"昏"天暗地吧
Knock yourself out.
或者更好的 拳击场上把别人打"昏"吧
Or better still, knock someone else out.
杰 你要去哪儿
Jay, where you headed?
你不如就在这里和其他当爹的喝杯啤酒吧
Why don't you stick around and grab a beer with the dads?
我都不认识这些人
Oh, I don't really know those guys.
我想我还是去趟俱乐部 打打球吧
I think I'll just swing by the club, hit a few balls.
来吧 我介绍你跟他们认识
Well, come here. Let me introduce you around.
嘿 伙计们
Hey, guys,
这位是杰 我的岳父 曼尼的后爹
This is Jay, my father-in-law. Manny's stepdad.
你好吗 "杰冻"
Hey, what's up, Jay-lo?
够了伙计们 失陪了
Okay, guys, I'll see you later.
怎么了 杰
What's the matter, Jay?
不敢踏出自己的"舒适小世界"吗
Afraid to step outside your comfort zone?
我要把你遣返墨西哥
I will send you back to Mexico.
其实不是我叫你过来的 对吧
I didn't really call you, did I?
对 是我爸 不过我还以为你知道呢
No, my dad did. But I thought you knew.
我想对他大发雷霆
Ugh. I want to be so mad at him,
可他是对的
but he's right.
我现在身上有两个脑袋
I have two brains in my body,
却史无前例得傻
but I've never been so dumb.
正常 我理解你
It happens. I get it.
你身体里还有另外一个人
You have another human being inside of you,
跟你争夺营养
competing for resources.
当年我怀艾丽克斯的时候
Look, when I was pregnant with Alex,
我连自己叫什么都记不住
I could barely remember my name.
怀海莉和卢克的时候也这样吗
Same with Haley and Luke?
没那么严重
Mm, not so much.
他们好像就在里面闲着似的 随便我做什么
They kind of just hung out in there, let me do my thing.
谢谢你理解我
Thank you for understanding.
你过来我真高兴
I'm glad that you came.
有助于避免我忘了什么事儿
It will help me not to forget stuff.
我也很高兴能帮上忙 我...
I'm glad I can help out. I--
你为什么不先停车
Why didn't you stop first?!
大爸在哪儿
Where's daddy?
我不知道 亲爱的
I don't know, sweetie.
他告诉我在欧娜树那里见
He said to meet him by Tree-ona.
米奇尔 莉莉
Mitchell! Lily!
他在哪儿
Where is he?
上面 往上看
Up here! Look up here!
小卡 你在上面干嘛
Cam, what are you doing up there?
我本来想过来和这棵树道别
I came down to say good bye to the tree,
给它最后一个拥抱
give it one final hug,
不知道怎么 就上来了
and before I knew it, I was up here.
你刚说"最后一个拥抱"其实是...
When you say "One final hug"...
要是我占住这棵树 他们就不会砍它了
If I'm occupying the tree, they can't cut it down.
我谷歌了一下 是真的
I googled it. It's a thing.
莉莉 你看 这就是个噩梦
Okay, Lily, see, this is a nightmare.
那还用你说
Tell me about it.
说实话 你喜欢列好要做的事 提前规划
You know what? You're a list-maker, a planner.
我是践行者和实干家
I'm a doer and an action taker!
如果他们拍这种电影 会找西恩·潘演我
Sean Penn would play me in a movie about this,
如果他们想拍女性题材的 会找安妮·海瑟薇
or Anne Hathaway, if they wanted a female-driven vehicle.
那会找谁扮演你饱受折磨的伴侣呢
And who would play your long-suffering partner?
朱莉安·摩尔 两种都是她
Julianne Moore, either way.
我能看出来 我能 我知道
I would totally see that. I would.
你好 我领导想知道
Hey! My supervisor wants to know
你有没有精神病史
if you have a history of mental illness.
没有 先生 我没有
No, sir, I do not.
好了 小卡 说来听听 有什么计划
All right, Cam, let's hear. What's the plan?
我不知道 我是走一步看一步
I don't know. I'm sort of making it up as I go.
你确定你想要这么做
Are you sure you wanna do this?
我这辈子从来没对什么事这么确定过
Yes. I've never been more sure about anything in my life.
我们得教会女儿树立坚定立场的价值
We need to teach our daughter the value of taking a stand,
无论付出什么代价
no matter the sacrifice!
喂
Hello?
好的 我立刻就来
Done. I'll be right there .
米奇尔 你得上树来 我得走了
Mitchell, you need to get up here. I have to go.
什么
Excuse me?
是我们歌剧团打来的 有个演员病了
That was my theater troupe. An actor's sick.
我得过去 顶一场日场演出
I have to go and do the matinee.
不是说要教莉莉树立坚定的立场吗
What happened to showing Lily the value of taking a stand?
那可是个主角
It's the lead.
向她展现一个人信守承诺
It's also important to show her the value
也是非常重要的
of honoring one's commitments.
这种情况下 我的承诺优先于我的立场
And in this case, my commitment preceded my stand!
真是你的一贯作风 小卡
This is so you, Cam.
你发起一件事 却总指望我替你收场
You start something, and then you expect me to finish it.
所以你是不会上来的是吗
So you're not coming up here?
不 我才不 走吧
No! No, I'm not. Come on.
米奇尔
Mitchell?
莉莉第一次翻身那天我们在哪儿
Where were we the first day Lily rolled over?
在这棵树下
Under this tree.
我们第一次玩藏猫猫的大本部在哪儿
Where is home base when we play hide-and-go-seek?
在这棵树下
Under this tree.
还有 在危险的暴雨闪电中
And where did we take shelter
我们的避难所在哪儿
during that dangerous lightning storm?
虽然那不是个好主意 不过是在这棵树下
Wasn't a good idea, but it was under this tree.
爹地 你一定要救救这棵树
Daddy, you've got to save the tree!
是啊 爹地 你得救救这棵树
Yeah, daddy, you have to save the tree!
行 好吧
Okay, okay.
但你完事以后立马给我回来
But you get back here the second you are done.
我不擅长拒绝那些冲到后台求签名的粉丝
Well, I can't very well turn away fans that come backstage.
立马回来
The second!
去年夏天 我姐拍了一张我的大糗照
Last summer, my sister took a totally humiliating photo of me.
海莉 这不好笑
Haley, that's not funny!
她把照片发到了Facebook上
Then she posted it to Facebook
并且拒绝删掉
and refused to take it down.
有873个人赞
It got 873 likes.
与此同时 我却一张海莉的糗照都没有
Meanwhile, there's not one embarrassing photo of Haley.
连她的犯罪照都很漂亮
Even her mug shots were cute.
今天 我要报仇雪恨
Today, I get my revenge.
拍一张海莉脏兮兮 汗淋淋
One photo of Haley, dirty, sweaty,
像罪犯一样捡垃圾的照片
picking up trash like a criminal.
那会成为我最得意的时刻
It'll be my finest moment.
我希望自己能在近几年内多交些朋友
In a few years, I hope to have some more friends
别再闲到干这种事的地步
and not have time for this kind of stuff.
我回来了
Okay. Hey.
你去哪了
Where did you go?
去拿了件运动衫
To get a sweatshirt.
我们已经在速冻食品区站了半个小时了
We've been standing in the frozen food aisle for half an hour.
我要买速冻食品
I need something frozen.
好 买哪个
Right. What?
不知道 我只写了一个"冻"字
I don't know. I just wrote the word "frozen."
好吧 好好想想
Okay. Uh, let's think.
豌豆 冰激凌 冻比萨饼还是华夫饼
Peas. Ice cream. Pizza. Waffles.
等一下
Wait a minute.
我写的是"打"字 我要买的是鸡蛋
It says "dozen." I need the eggs!
是鸡蛋啊 好
Ah, the eggs. Okay.
不对 在另一边
Ay, no, on the other side.
老天 我 我来推车
Oh, god. I-I'll get the carts.
真是... 抱歉
So that's... Oh, sorry.
那辆也是我的 是我的 我抓住了
That's... That's me. That's me. I got it.
加把劲 伙计们 我们快顶不住了
Come on, guys! You're killing us!
墨西哥小子跑哪去了
Where the heck is Mexico?
好消息 先生们 我又找到一根绳子
Good news, gentlemen! I found another rope.
我们可以玩跳双绳 大家双赢多好
If we double-dutch, everyone wins.
好 别动
Okay, hold still...
等一下
And wait for it...
来瞧瞧你发胖加秃顶以后的样子
This is what you'd look like fat and bald.
我自拍一张 不装那个应用也是这样的效果
On my phone, that app's called a camera.
比尔 别这么妄自菲薄
Bill, don't do that to yourself.
告诉你吧 艾琳是个幸运的女人
Let me tell you something. Ellen is one lucky woman.
这有什么好笑的
Why is that funny?
因为她老公是杰瑞而不是比尔
Because she's married to Jerry.
杰 你手机里有什么好玩的应用
Jay, you got any good apps?
不知道 我有呼叫等待功能 那算吗
I don't know. I got call waiting. Is that an app?
你们很爱笑 是吧
You guys laugh a lot, huh?
杰对电子产品不太在行
Jay's a little technologically challenged.
你个不会开手动挡车的人还敢说我
From a guy who can't drive a stick.
-什么 -你真不会吗
- What? - You can't?
有一次他打电话叫我去营救他
Well... he called me to rescue him one time.
他停在一个坡上 不敢松离合器
He got stuck on a hill. He was afraid to let go of the clutch.
我赶到的时候
By the time I got there,
他后面排了半英里长的车队
traffic's backed up half a mile,
所有人都在冲他嚷嚷 他急得直哭
everybody's yelling at him. He's in tears.
我没哭 是出的汗
Not tears. Maybe sweat.
是 他眼睛出了汗
Yeah, sweatin' out your eyes.
我拍到了差不多10张海莉的糗照
I had about ten pretty bad pictures of Haley.
我本可以就此收手
I could have quit right there,
但我是个完美主义者
but I'm a perfectionist.
我琢磨着
I thought,
"我能做得更好 我会拍到更难看的"
"I could do better. She could look worse."
天呐
Oh, my god.
行了 哥们
All right, pal.
从树上下来吧
Come down from the tree.
抱歉 我做不到
Sorry, can't do that.
再不下来我们就把你拽下来
Come down before we pull you down.
淡定 别动粗
W--hey. Ease up.
有什么问题
What's the problem?
听着 我也不想呆在树上
Look, I don't want to be up here.
懂吗 但这是我女儿最心爱的一棵树
You know? But this is my daughter's favorite tree.
我家男人 他也竭力反对
And my partner-- he's all up in arms
他们把树砍掉 所以...
about them cutting it down, so...
你男人既然那么热衷 他为什么没来
Well, if your partner's so worked up, why isn't he here?
你这问题问得真好
Oh, well, that's a very good question.
那是因为他习惯了做事有始无终
It's because he starts things, and he doesn't finish them,
所以我就要替他收场
so then I have to.
跟我老婆一模一样
Just like my wife.
我的心理医生会说我们这样是在纵容他们
You know, my therapist would say we're "enabling" them.
又是你的心理医生
You and your therapist.
要不是你枪击了那家伙 我也不用去看心理医生啊
I wouldn't have to see him if you hadn't shot that guy.
不是吧 又来
Aw, that again?
我们用消防水管把他喷下来得了
Look, let's just spray him with the fire hose.
你只会越帮越忙 泰瑞
You're not helping, Terry.
那不是你的"战斗"
It's not your fight.
所以你何不给我们个面子
So why don't you do us a favor,
从树上下来吧
and come on down?
因为他是对的 懂吗
Because he's right, all right?
那是最让我无奈的
That's the frustrating part.
我在这上面坐了几个小时了
I-I've been sitting up here these past few hours,
而且 这棵树很漂亮 好吗
and... this tree is beautiful, okay?
我能听到小松鼠们在树枝间穿梭的声音
And I-I can hear the squirrels dancing through the branches,
他们追逐嬉戏
you know, chasing each other,
全然不知这乐园要被摧毁了
no idea what's about to happen.
你知道吗 这不只是一棵树
You know, this isn't just a tree.
而是一个家园
This is a home.
没错 一大家子老鼠的家园
Yeah, to, like, a hundred rats.
树上到处都是老鼠
They're all over this thing.
你说什么都没有用
Well, that changes nothing.
要是有必要 我会在这跟你们耗一晚上
I will wait you guys out all night if I have to.
小卡 给你20分钟
Cam, you got 20 minutes,
再不回来我就下去了
and I'm out of this tree.
泰瑞 去把消防水管准备好吧
Terry, you wanna get ready with that hose?
有一天艾丽克斯放学回来
So Alex comes home from school the other day,
跟我说她老师听不懂她说的话
and she said the teacher didn't know what she was talking about,
但实际上 我不觉得...
when in reality, I don't think that--
你差点把我的头砍下来
You almost just cut my head off.
你得注意点
You gotta focus.
对不起 到头来 我还是忘了买鸡蛋
I am sorry. After all that, I forgot the eggs!
-打扰一下 -你等会儿
- Excuse me. - Yeah, hang on one second.
听我说 你犯傻不只是因为怀孕
Listen, this is not just your pregnancy.
你这是故意让你的大脑停工
You are purposely turning your brain off.
你至少得有意识地稍微注意一点
You have to at least try to pay attention.
-女士 -怎么
- Ma'am? - Yeah.
你有这件运动衫的收据吗
Do you have a receipt for that sweatshirt?
糟糕
Oh, shoot.
你得跟我回商场一趟
I'm gonna need you to come back into the store.
不 不 我只是忘了我还穿着它了
Oh, no. No, it's--I forgot I was wearing it.
没什么要紧的 给你
It's no big deal. Here.
女士 跟我回商场
Ma'am. The store.
别开玩笑了
Are you kidding me?
我真没想偷这运动衫
I didn't try to steal a sweatshirt!
先生 我可是位母亲
Sir, I'm a mom.
歌洛莉亚 帮帮我
Gloria, help me out.
听好了 警察先生
Listen, Mr. Policeman,
我们真要偷
If we wanted to steal it,
你压根不可能发觉它不见了
You wouldn't even know that it was gone!
行了 你这是帮倒忙
Yeah, okay. That's not helping.
天呐 一只金手镯
Oh, my god! A gold bracelet!
捡到的东西能归我们吗
Hey, can we keep what we find?
无语了
Unbelievable.
不是吧
Really?
先生们 你们想知道
Gentlemen, you wanna know about
什么是真正的飞盘比赛吗
the real ultimate frisbee?
头顶着飞盘走50米不让它掉下来
Walk with one balanced on your head for 50 meters.
它需要你的姿势 平衡和体态
It is a measure of poise, balance, and posture.
我们就尽可能用力地相互扔飞盘吧
Let's just whip the frisbees at each other as hard as we can
看谁第一个退出
and see who quits first.
飞盘大战
Frisbee smash.
酷毙了 开始吧
Awesome! Let's go!
天呐 我苦命得和西西弗似的
Oh, my god, I'm Sisyphus.
大苦逼
A big one!
他当时在我家院子 提了个录放机
So he's out in our yard and he's got a boombox...
那个提录放机情节的电影叫什么来着
What's the name of that movie with the boombox?
-《情到深处》 -约翰·马奥尼演的
- Oh, "Say anything." - With John Mahoney.
总之 他就站在那儿
So anyway, he's out there,
恳请克莱尔原谅他
And he's begging Claire for forgiveness.
但她还在气头上 完全听不进去
She's still mad at him. She won't have any of it.
然后他把音量开到最大
So he turns it up full-blast,
放的竟然是奥莉维亚·纽顿-约翰的歌
And it's Olivia Newton-John.
他就开始唱《让我们一起"菲动"》
And he starts singing, "Let's get Phil-sical"!
那是个小范围的内部笑话
It was an inside joke.
不再是喽
Well, not anymore!
行啦 开心果菲尔的故事就到此为止吧
Okay, enough with the funny Phil stories.
别啊 我还没说到最精彩的地方呢
No, but I haven't even gotten to the best part yet.
他还载歌载舞 我当时真心看不下去了
So he's doing his little dance, and I can't take it anymore,
就对准他开了洒水器
So I nail him with the sprinklers!
是啊 你还把我的录放机搞短路了
Yep, and you also shorted out my boombox,
你当时说会赔我一个 到现在也没影
which you said you'd replace and you never did.
我肯定没那样说过
I never said that!
你真说过 你现在还欠我个录放机
Yes, you did. You still owe me one boombox,
12节D型电池
12 "D" batteries,
和一盒奥莉维亚·纽顿-约翰磁带
and an Olivia Newton-John cassingle.
好吧 那...
Okay, uh...
我们在拳击场里解决这事吧
Why don't we settle it in the ring?
我们去那较量
We get in there,
如果你赢了 要什么录放机我都给你买
and if you beat me, I'll buy you any boombox you want.
如果我赢了
If I beat you,
你就得在大家面前跳那舞
then you've gotta do your little dance for everyone.
我应战
I'm in.
我们"菲动"起来
Let's get Phil-sical.
我一点都不担心 当海军时我打过拳击
I wasn't worried. I'd boxed in the navy.
而且对手是菲尔
And it was Phil.
我从没想到我会说这种话
And here's something I thought I'd never say--
我宁愿和我女婿打 也不愿和我"儿婿"打
I'd rather box my daughter's husband than my son's.
或许对杰 我一直酝酿着一丝丝怒气
I may have been holding on to a tiny bit of anger towards Jay.
我卖了整整一夏天的冰淇淋才买了那台录放机
I scooped ice cream all summer for that boombox!
不好意思 让一让 我们来了
Excuse me. Pardon me. We're here!
我们紧赶着到了
We came as fast as we could!
你就不能换身衣服吗
You couldn't change?
不是你说立马过来吗
You said come right away!
打扰一下 女士们先生们
Excuse me, ladies and gentlemen!
奥克伍德剧院出品的音乐剧《猫》
Oakwood Rep's production of "Cats"!
确保这周不要错过哦
Make sure you catch it this week.
小道消息都说替角儿在里面大出风头了呢
Word on the street is the understudy steals the show!
米奇尔 我又获得了两个表演机会
Mitchell, I get two more shows!
多亏肯尼·范·海辛顿的脚趾甲感染了
Kenny Van Heffington's toenail is infected!
赶紧上来 好吗
Just get up here, all right?
工作人员天黑才走
The crew has to leave at dark,
所以你得坚持到那时候
so you have until then.
小菜一碟
Easy peasy.
宝贝 跟二爸说你觉得我的表演怎么样
Sweetie, tell daddy what you thought of my performance.
出类拔萃
Transcendent.
我的天
Oh, jeez.
是树液吗
Is this sap?
我都买了几百美元的商品了
Why would I buy hundreds of dollars worth of merchandise
为什么还要偷件20美元的运动衫
and then steal a $20 sweatshirt?
我不知道 或许你是要找刺激
I don't know. Maybe you do it for the thrill.
你这类人我见得多了
I know your type.
无聊的家庭主妇 开辆小面包
You're a bored housewife, drives a minivan,
丈夫沉迷网络
husband spends a little too much time online.
有两个孩子 和一个派不上用场的大学文凭
Got a couple of kids, a college degree you don't use.
你错得太离谱了
You could not be more wrong.
没错 她有仨孩子呢
Yes. She has three kids.
行了 不 不用了
Okay, no. No, no.
不 不 不用了 你别帮倒忙了
No, no. No, that's not helping.
听着 我已经说过了 那纯属意外
Look, as I said before, it was an accident.
你这种话我听过不下千遍了
Heard it a thousand times.
老奶奶 商人 资优生
Grandmothers, businessmen, honor students--
他们都这么说
They all say the same thing--
"那纯属意外
"It was an accident.
我也不知道那个收音机闹钟
I don't know how that clock radio
怎么到我裤子里来的"
got in my pants."
看在上帝份上 我身体不舒服
Oh, for god sake! I don't feel well.
让我们走吧
Let us go.
想得美
Yeah, right.
那真是个婴儿吗
Is that even a baby?
因为从我这角度看过去 跟个火鸡似的
'Cause from here, it looks like a turkey.
我要你在这上面签字 承认你有罪
I need you to sign this, admitting your guilt,
保证再也不上我们商场来
and promising you'll never return to this store.
我才不会签这字
I'm not signing that.
那好
Okay, great.
那我就只能报警 被迫...
Then I'm gonna call the police and I'll be forced to--
那是什么
What was that?
我的羊水破了
My water broke!
我要生了
I'm having the baby!
对不起 我刚才失控了
Sorry about that. I went a little nuts there.
不知道怎么会这样
I don't know what happened.
我知道
I do.
我在你朋友面前大爆你的糗事
I was ragging on you in front of your friends.
-是哦 -对不起
- Oh, yeah. - Sorry about that.
我想不到还能说些什么
I couldn't think of anything else to say.
为什么
Why not?
我跟他们有20到25年的代沟
I got 20, 25 years on those guys.
没什么共同语言
We got nothing in common.
而且情况只会更糟
It's only gonna get worse.
想想看 10年后我和新宝宝相处会是什么状况
I mean, what's it gonna be like with the new kid in ten years?
我的老天
Oh, my goodness.
你缺乏安全感 脆弱无助
You're insecure and vulnerable.
我从没见过你这么可爱的样子
This is the cutest thing I've ever seen.
闭嘴
Shut up.
瞧这只害羞的兔兔
Who's a shy bunny?
你想不戴手套再来一回合吗
You wanna go one more round, without the gloves?
开个玩笑嘛 杰
I'm just playing around, Jay.
我不在乎你多大年纪
I don't care how old you are.
我可以整天和你聊个没完
I could sit and talk to you all day.
那些家伙也是真的喜欢你
Those guys really liked you, too.
我才不在乎
I don't care about that.
真的吗
Did they?
-连杰瑞都喜欢我 -是的
- Even Jerry? - Yes.
也许你是对的
Well, maybe you're right.
曼尼根本就不想来 你瞧他
I mean, Manny didn't want to come, and look at him.
他看起来玩得非常开心
Looks like he's having a great time.
然后卢克的爸爸从我这里抢走了电击枪
So then Luke's dad grabs the taser from me,
-然后他就这样 -不 不是
- and he was like, "Uhh! Uhh!" - No. No!
事情不是这样的
That's not how it happened.
妈呀 好痛
Aah! Ay! Ay! It hurts!
坚持下 坚持下
Hang in there! Hang in there!
我会尽快送你去医院
Get you to the hospital as soon as I can!
我代表超市
I just want to apologize...
再次表达歉意
one more time on behalf of the store
抱歉可能给你带来了压力
for any stress that I might have caused you.
给 这件运动衫就当作是礼物吧
Here, you can keep the sweatshirt as a gift.
恭喜你喜得贵子
And congratulations on this baby,
很显然这不是火鸡 那只是...
which is clearly not a turkey. That was--
-快滚开 -快走
- Go away now! - Yeah.
快上车 快点
Okay. Go on. Go on. Get in. Keep going.
我们要去哪家医院
What hospital are we going to?
-不去医院 -不去医院 哇
- No! No hospital! - No hospital. Wow.
你是在家生产的人啊
You're one of those, huh?
好吧 请别在游泳池里生
Okay, please don't have it in the pool, though.
我们还要游泳的
'cause we swim in there.
我还没到生的时候 克莱尔
I'm not having the baby, Claire.
我只是假装的
I was just faking it.
什么
What?
怀孕的傻脑瓜还能转得这么快 不错吧
Not bad for someone with pregnancy brain, huh?
非常好 真是太好了
Okay, that's good. That was very good.
脑子转得真快 歌洛莉亚
Good thinking, Gloria.
抱歉 我不能坐在那里
I'm sorry. I just couldn't sit there
眼巴巴地看着你
and watch you suffer
就因为脑子停工了而遭罪
just because you had turned your brain off.
好吧 是我活该
Okay, I deserved that.
不要 不要啊
Oh, no. Oh, no, no, no, no.
我刚闯了个红灯 见鬼
I just blew through a red light. Damn.
你可以再装下
You think you can keep the pregnancy thing up
快生孩子了吗
for a little while longer?
头快出来了
I feel the head!
出来了 出来了
Feel it! Feel it!
等会儿 留着在警察面前装
Save it! Save it for the cop!
留着
Save it.
好了伙计们 下班了 收工吧
All right, guys, that's it. Pack it up!
今天算你狠 我们周一见
You win for today. See you on Monday.
就这样完了吗
That's it?
就这样完了
That's it.
我周一会去市政厅
So I'll go to city hall on Monday
看看有没有办法
and see what I can do,
但是 你成功了 小卡
But... You did it, cam!
不 我们成功了
No, we did it.
我有急事离开 你就挺身而出
I had to run away, and you stepped in,
就像替补演员 奉献了精彩的表演
and like an understudy, you gave a brilliant performance.
但你才是明星
Yeah, but you're the star.
好吧
Oh, well...
可以不玩这个了回家吗
Can we stop doing this and go home?
好的 莉莉 但我希望你记住这一时刻
Yes, Lily, but I want you to remember this moment--
你大爸二爸让你骄傲的一天
The day your daddies made you proud.
别让她看 米奇尔 别让她看
Turn her away, Mitchell! Turn her away!
艾丽克斯 你在这里做什么
Alex, what are you doing here?
学习关于因果报应的宝贵一课
Learning a valuable lesson about karma
以及利用别人的糗事来取乐
and how wrong it is to take pleasure
是非常错误的
in people's embarrassment.
哇 我完全不懂你在说什么
Wow. I don't know what any of that means,
不过你的样子好惨
but you look like hell.
-说"呆子" -不
- Say "Geek." - No!
他是个"破坏者"哦
He's a vandalizer!
593个赞 人数继续上升中
593 likes, and counting.
这是谁家走失的小猫咪
Who does he belong to?
我家的
He's mine.
美妙的一天有了一个美妙的结局
It was a great ending to an amazing day.
瞧 我甚至 上了报
Look, I even... Made the paper.
古怪抗议拯救公园树木
"Bizarre protest saves park tree."
看这里写的
Oh, look what it says.
本版音乐剧《猫》该永远不得面世
"This production of 'Cats' should be put to sleep."
别看那个
Don't read that.
别
Don't...
你好 歌洛莉亚
Oh, hey, Gloria.
我打了电话给杰 借个电钻
Listen, I called Jay about borrowing a drill
装抽屉柜的把手
for my dresser handles.
我拿来了 小卡
I got it right here, Cam!
老天 怎么穿成这样
Oh, jeez. What's with the getup?
太好了 原来我没做梦
Ay, good. You see that, too?
斯黛拉 别这样
Stella, stop.
安静 抱歉 小卡
Ay, shh, shh, shh. Sorry, Cam.
别这样 它这是在恭维我栩栩如生呢
Oh, no, don't be. I take it as a compliment.
《猫》 直到永恒
"Cats"--now and forever.
事实上 只到下周四
Actually, just till next Thursday.
演出被形容为"出类拔萃"
It's been described as "Transcendent."